export const chapter = "Chapter - 11: Let's See a Family in Transit";
export const noOfActivities = 3;

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 1) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Tick the correct option:",
    questions: [
      {
        questions: [
          {
            question: "What is a family tree typically used to represent?",
            options: [
              "A) Economic relationships within a family",
              "B) Three generations of people and their relationships in a family",
              "C) Environmental impact on a family",
            ],
            answer:
              "B) Three generations of people and their relationships in a family",
          },
          {
            question:
              "What are the primary reasons for family migration mentioned in the text?",
            options: [
              "A) Cultural changes",
              "B) Social, economic, and environmental reasons",
              "C) Educational advancements",
            ],
            answer: "B) Social, economic, and environmental reasons",
          },
          {
            question:
              "What is the term used for the large-scale movement of people from one place to another in search of a new beginning?",
            options: ["A) Immigration", "B) Migration", "C) Relocation"],
            answer: "B) Migration",
          },
          {
            question: "What are people who migrate called?",
            options: ["A) Nomads", "B) Travellers", "C) Migrants"],
            answer: "C) Migrants",
          },
          {
            question:
              "In a temporary migration, what do migrants do after completing their desired tasks?",
            options: [
              "A) Settle permanently in the new place",
              "B) Return to their original place",
              "C) Continue migrating to other places",
            ],
            answer: "B) Return to their original place",
          },
          {
            question:
              "What are the three primary reasons for migration mentioned in the text?",
            options: [
              "A) Social, political, and cultural",
              "B) Social, economic, and environmental",
              "C) Environmental, economic, and educational",
            ],
            answer: "B) Social, economic, and environmental",
          },
          {
            question: "What does the term 'family tree' illustrate?",
            options: [
              "A) Economic status of a family",
              "B) Three-dimensional structure of a family",
              "C) Relationships within a family over three generations",
            ],
            answer: "C) Relationships within a family over three generations",
          },
          {
            question:
              "How do modern families differ from traditional families according to the text?",
            options: [
              "A) Modern families follow old customs.",
              "B) Modern families don't adopt new methods.",
              "C) Modern families change with cultural, educational, and living standards advancements.",
            ],
            answer:
              "C) Modern families change with cultural, educational, and living standards advancements.",
          },
          {
            question:
              "What is the term used for people who do the work with their own will and interest, according to the text?",
            options: ["A) Traditionalists", "B) Free agents", "C) Modernists"],
            answer: "B) Free agents",
          },
          {
            question:
              "What is the result of harmful environmental impacts, such as drought, earthquake, and cyclone, mentioned in the text?",
            options: [
              "A) Economic growth",
              "B) Migration",
              "C) Stability in family life",
            ],
            answer: "B) Migration",
          },
        ],
      },
    ],
  };
}

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 2) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Fill in the blanks:",
    questions: [
      {
        questions: [
          {
            question:
              "A family is a group of people related to one another. It is made up of __________ and their children.",
            options: ["A) Friends", "B) Siblings", "C) Parents"],
            answer: "C) Parents",
          },
          {
            question:
              "A family tree usually shows all the people in a family over __________ generations and their relationships with one another.",
            options: ["A) Two", "B) Three", "C) Four"],
            answer: "B) Three",
          },
          {
            question:
              "Sometimes, a family may have to move due to social, economic, or __________ reasons.",
            options: ["A) Political", "B) Educational", "C) Environmental"],
            answer: "C) Environmental",
          },
          {
            question:
              "Abnormal changes in society leading to discomfort is a primary cause of shifting due to __________ reasons.",
            options: ["A) Economic", "B) Social", "C) Cultural"],
            answer: "B) Social",
          },
          {
            question:
              "To raise their standard of living, a family might decide to change locations due to __________ reasons.",
            options: ["A) Social", "B) Economic", "C) Cultural"],
            answer: "B) Economic",
          },
          {
            question:
              "Migration is the large-scale movement of people from one place to another in search of a new __________.",
            options: ["A) Tradition", "B) Beginning", "C) Adventure"],
            answer: "B) Beginning",
          },
          {
            question:
              "People who migrate are commonly referred to as __________.",
            options: ["A) Nomads", "B) Travelers", "C) Migrants"],
            answer: "C) Migrants",
          },
          {
            question:
              "In a temporary migration, migrants may return after completing their __________ tasks.",
            options: ["A) Educational", "B) Desired", "C) Cultural"],
            answer: "B) Desired",
          },
          {
            question:
              "With advancements in culture and education, traditional families often transform into __________ families.",
            options: ["A) Conservative", "B) Modern", "C) Extended"],
            answer: "B) Modern",
          },
          {
            question:
              "People now work with their own will and interest, reflecting a shift from traditional __________.",
            options: ["A) Jobs", "B) Customs", "C) Practices"],
            answer: "B) Customs",
          },
        ],
      },
    ],
  };
}

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 3) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Write 'True' for True and 'False' for False statements:",
    questions: [
      {
        questions: [
          {
            question:
              "A family tree usually shows people in a family over three generations and their relationships with one another.",
            options: ["True", "False"],
            answer: "True",
          },
          {
            question:
              "Migration is the large-scale movement of people from one place to another in search of a new beginning.",
            options: ["True", "False"],
            answer: "True",
          },
          {
            question:
              "In temporary migration, migrants do not come back after completing their desired tasks.",
            options: ["True", "False"],
            answer: "False",
          },
          {
            question:
              "Modern families often change with cultural, educational, and living standards advancements.",
            options: ["True", "False"],
            answer: "True",
          },
          {
            question:
              "Environmental reasons, such as drought and cyclones, can force people to move from their place to another.",
            options: ["True", "False"],
            answer: "True",
          },
          {
            question:
              "The term 'family tree' illustrates the economic status of a family.",
            options: ["True", "False"],
            answer: "False",
          },
          {
            question:
              "People who migrate are commonly referred to as travelers.",
            options: ["True", "False"],
            answer: "False",
          },
          {
            question:
              "In a permanent migration, migrants come back after completing their desired tasks.",
            options: ["True", "False"],
            answer: "False",
          },
          {
            question:
              "Social, economic, and environmental reasons are mentioned as primary causes of family migration.",
            options: ["True", "False"],
            answer: "True",
          },
          {
            question:
              "With advancements in culture and education, most traditional families change into modern families.",
            options: ["True", "False"],
            answer: "True",
          },
        ],
      },
    ],
  };
}

export var activityData;
